const questions = [
    {
        "Question": "Who is Edwards VI's father?",
        "correct": "Henry VIII",
        "incorrect1": "Henry VII",
        "incorrect2": "Charles II ",
        "incorrect3": "George III",
        id : 0
    },
    {
        "Question": "Henry VIII’s marriage to which woman led to his break with the Roman Catholic Church?",
        "correct": "Anne Boleyn",
        "incorrect1": "Catherine Parr",
        "incorrect2": "Catherine of Aragon",
        "incorrect3": "Jane Seymour",
        id : 1,
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which queen of England was known as “the Virgin Queen?",
        "correct": "Elizabeth I",
        "incorrect1": "Anne of Cleaves",
        "incorrect2": "Catherine of Aragon",
        "incorrect3": "Mary I",
        id : 2,
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which principal adviser to Henry VIII was eventually executed, in 1540, for heresy and treason?",
        "correct": "Thomas Cromwell",
        "incorrect1": "Oliver Cromwell",
        "incorrect2": "Thomas More",
        "incorrect3": "Thomas Becket",
        id : 3,
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who led a formidable uprising against Mary I?",
        "correct": "Sir Thomas Wyatt the Younger",
        "incorrect1": "Guy Fawkes",
        "incorrect2": "Thomas Wolsey",
        "incorrect3": "Richard Cromwell",
        id : 4,
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which English statesman and adviser to Henry VIII was the son of a butcher?",
        "correct": "Thomas Wolsey",
        "incorrect1": "Thomas Cromwell",
        "incorrect2": "Thomas More",
        "incorrect3": "Richard Nanfan",
        id : 5,
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who was the titular queen of England for nine days in 1553?",
        "correct": "Lady Jane Grey",
        "incorrect1": "Catherine of Aragon",
        "incorrect2": "Anne Boleyn",
        "incorrect3": "Mary, Queen of Scots",
        id : 6,
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which archbishop of Canterbury was burned at the stake for heresy during the Tudor period?",
        "correct": "Thomas Cranmer",
        "incorrect1": "Thomas Cromwell",
        "incorrect2": "Thomas Becket",
        "incorrect3": "Stephen Langton",
        id : 7,
    },
    {
        "Question": "Which English admiral circumnavigated the globe between 1577 and 1580?",
        "correct": "Francis Drake",
        "incorrect1": "Walter Raleigh",
        "incorrect2": "Humphrey Gilbert",
        "incorrect3": "John Davis",
        id : 8,
    },
    {
        "Question": "Who did Henry VII, the first Tudor King, defeat at the Battle of Bosworth in 1485 in order to take the throne?",
        "correct": "Richard II",
        "incorrect1": "Richard I",
        "incorrect2": "Richard III",
        "incorrect3": "Charles II",
        id : 9,
    },
    {
        "Question": " To secure his position, and to end the Wars of the Roses, who did Henry VII marry in 1486?",
        "correct": "Elizabeth Woodville",
        "incorrect1": "Anne Neville",
        "incorrect2": "Elizabeth of York",
        "incorrect3": "Agnes of Aragon",
        id : 10,
    },
    {
        "Question": "Edward VI, The Boy King, was only nine years old when he became King at the death of his father, Henry VIII. Who governed in his stead?",
        "correct": "Edward Seymour",
        "incorrect1": "Thomas Seymour",
        "incorrect2": "Robert Dudley",
        "incorrect3": "Thomas of Cleves",
        id : 11,
    },
    {
        "Question": "In which royal palace did Henry VII die on 21 April 1509?",
        "correct": "Richmond Palace",
        "incorrect1": "Hampton Court Palace",
        "incorrect2": "Whitehall Palace",
        "incorrect3": "Cheltstire Abbey",
        id : 12,
    },
    {
        "Question": "Henry VIII was eighteen years old when he became King in 1509. Who did he marry that same year?",
        "correct": "Catherine Of Aragon",
        "incorrect1": "Anne of Cleves",
        "incorrect2": "Anne Boleyn",
        "incorrect3": "Jane Seymour",
        id : 13,
    },
    {
        "Question": "Henry VIII is famous for having married six times. Which of his wives, beheaded by him in 1536, was the mother of Queen Elizabeth I?",
        "correct": "Anne Boleyn",
        "incorrect1": "Catherine Howard",
        "incorrect2": "Catherine Parr",
        "incorrect3": "Anne of Cleves",
        id : 14,
    },
    {
        "Question": "Henry VIII died on 28 January 1547 at Whitehall Palace. For how many years had he reigned as king?",
        "correct": "37 Years",
        "incorrect1": "44 Years",
        "incorrect2": "29 Years",
        "incorrect3": "33 Years",
        id : 15,
    }
]
module.exports = questions
